（上条(かみじょう)）
俺は聞いちまったんだ
Now, I've heard it...
インデックスは 本当に―
...the fact that Index really has
committed 103,000 grimoires to memory...
10万3,000冊の魔道書を
記憶していることを
だから 狙われているってことを
...which is why she is being targeted...
なのに 彼女は たったの一度も
“助けてくれ”とは言わなかった
Yet, she never said "help me" even once.
俺は… 俺は…
～♪
I...
#04 Perfect Memorization
Huh?
There's... no one?
人がいない？
It's just a rune.
（神裂(かんざき)）ルーン
（上条）ハッ…
（神裂）
人払いのルーンを
刻んでいるだけですよ
A rune that removed all people from here.
てめえは…
You're...
Kanzaki Kaori is my name.
神裂火織(かおり)と申します
（神裂）
できれば もうひとつの
名は語りたくないのですが
I would rather not mention my other name.
（上条）
もうひとつ？
Your other name?
（神裂）魔法名ですよ
（上条）ハッ…
My magic name, that is.
You're from the Magic Cabal, like him?
あいつと同じ魔術結社の…
I will get straight to the point.
率直に言います
I wish to secure that girl before I mention my magic name.
魔法名を名乗る前に
彼女を保護したいのですが
And if I refuse?
（上条）
イヤだと言ったら？
Then I have no choice.
しかたありません
I'll just need to state my name, then secure her.
名乗ってから 彼女を保護するまで
I will repeat myself.
（神裂）もう一度 問います
（上条）えっ…
I wish to secure that girl...
魔法名を名乗る前に
彼女を保護したいのですが
...before I mention my magic name...
Wh-What are you talking about...
な… 何言ってやがる
てめえを相手に
降参する理由なんざ…
I have no reason...
...to surrender to you...
I will repeat myself as many times as necessary.
何度でも問います
（上条）
ウワッ！
The speed of the slash wreathed by my Shichiten Shichitou, Nanasen,
Note: Shichiten Shichitou literally means "Seven Heaven Seven Swords",
and Nanasen literally means "Seven Rays"
私の“七天七刀(しちてんしちとう)”が織りなす
“七閃(ななせん)”の斬撃速度は―
kills someone seven times over in a
time period we refer to as a "split second".
一瞬と呼ばれる時間に
７度 殺すレベルです
“必殺”と言っても
間違いではありませんが
I wouldn't think it's wrong to call it "certain death".
Shit...
くそ… １発も見えなかった
I couldn't even see a single slash.
But...
だけど この右手なら
With my right hand...
（神裂）
ステイルからの報告は受けています
I have received the report from Stiyl.
For some reason, your right hand can neutralize magic.
あなたの右手は
なぜか魔術を無効化する
But wouldn't that mean that as long as you don't touch it with your right hand,
ですが それは―
あなたが右手で触れないかぎり
不可能ではありませんか？
you wouldn't be able of doing that?
Now what?
（上条）
どうする？
思い切って 飛び込むか？
Leap straight at her without any thought?
七閃
Nanasen.
（上条）
ウワッ！
I will repeat myself as many times as necessary.
幾度でも問います… うん？
I do not understand what is driving you to fight so hard.
何が あなたをそこまで
駆り立てるのか分かりませんが
七閃
Nanasen.
Damn you!
ちくしょう！
It's not disappearing?
（上条）
消えない？
極細のワイヤー？
Ultra-thin wires?
こいつ
刀を動かす しぐさに隠して…
She... hides all these wires while she maneuvers her katana?
You're... not a magician?
あんた 魔術師じゃなかったのか？
I have just mentioned...
言ったはずです
ステイルから話を聞いていたと
...that I heard Stiyl's story...
Then your long katana's...
（上条）
なら その長い刀は？
My Shichiten Shichitou is not an object for decoration.
（神裂）
この七天七刀は
飾りではありませんよ
What awaits you after going through Nanasen, is the truth, "Yuisen".
Note: Yuisen literally translates to "The Only Ray"
七閃をくぐり抜けた先には
真説の“唯閃(ゆいせん)”が待っています
それに 何より
私は魔法名すら名乗っていません
More importantly, I have yet to mention my magic name.
名乗らせないでください 少年
Please do not make me mention it, young man.
I do not wish to mention that name ever again.
私は
もう二度と あれを名乗りたくない
Surrender? Never.
降参できるか
何ですか？
聞こえなかったのですが
What was that?
I couldn't hear you.
Shut up...
（上条）うるせえ
（神裂）うん？
うるせえっつったんだよ
この無感情野郎
I said, shut up.
You emotionless bastard.
Nanasen.
七閃
Isn't it quite enough?
もういいでしょう？
あなたが彼女に
そこまでする理由はないはずです
I don't believe you have any reason to be fighting this much for her.
Why...
なんでだよ…
なんで俺を殺さない？
Why aren't you killing me?
If you wanted to, you could've given me your "certain death" anytime.
その気になれば
俺をいつだって必殺できたくせに
You're still a person...
あんたは まだ―
そこで ためらってくれるだけの
常識ある人間なんだろう？
...that has enough sense to not kill me at this stage, right?
なら 分かんだろう
Then you should know why, right?
寄ってたかって
女の子を追い回して
Chasing a little girl through the crowds...
Slashing her back with your katana...
刀で背中 斬って
That shouldn't be tolerated...
そんなこと許されるはずないって
（上条）
知ってんのかよ？
Did you know?
She's lost her memories because of you people.
あいつ てめえらのせいで
記憶がなくなっちまってるんだぞ
どこまで ひどく追い詰めりゃ―
How badly did you chase her to make her lose even her memories?
そこまで
ひどいことになっちまうんだよ？
俺はさ 死にものぐるいで戦って
I'm the kind of loser that has to fight in a desperate fashion...
それでも たったひとりの女の子も
守れねえような負け犬だよ
...and yet not able to even protect one single girl...
I am just a weak being that can only chew on
my fingers as I watch you guys take her away...
（上条）
てめえらに連れ去られるのを―
指をくわえて
見ていることしかできねえ弱者だよ
...but you're different, no?
だけど あんたは違うんだろう？
そんな力があれば
誰だって何だって守れるのに
With the power you have, you can protect whoever and whatever you want...
何だって誰だって救えるのに
...you can save whoever and whatever you want...
...yet, why is this the only action you're taking?
なんで
そんなことしかできねえんだよ！
I'm not...
私だって…
私だって 好きで こんなことを
しているわけではありません
I'm not... doing this because I want to...
私の所属する組織の名前は
必要悪の教会(ネセサリウス)
The name of the organization I belong to...
...is Necessarius...
それって
インデックスと同じイギリス清教の
That's... the same one Index belongs to,
the English Purist Church!
She is my colleague...
彼女は 私の同僚にして―
...and a very important friend of mine...
大切な親友なんですよ
私だって
彼女の背中を斬るつもりはなかった
I didn't intend to slash her back either!
I didn't... know the Walking Church had been destroyed...
あれは “歩く教会”が
破壊されたとは知らず―
彼女が 絶対に
傷つくはずがないから斬っただけ
I only slashed her knowing she wouldn't be injured.
Yet...
なのに…
W-Wait!
ま… 待てよ
親友の背中をどうして…
Why did you even slash your friend from behind?
（神裂）
そうやって保護しないと
彼女は生きていけないんです
If I don't secure her in that manner, she won't be able to live.
Her "perfect memorization" ability...
完全記憶能力
Perfect... memorization?
完全記憶能力？
That is the reason behind all this.
（神裂）
それが全ての元凶です
（上条）
完全記憶能力って…
By perfect memorization...
10万3,000冊のことか？
...are you referring to the 103,000 grimoires?
She said they were all inputted into her brain.
（上条）
全部 あいつの頭の中に
入ってんだってな
（神裂）
人間の脳の容量は 意外に小さい
The human brain's capacity is rather minimal.
But, by forgetting unnecessary memories,
ですが
要らない記憶を忘れることで
知らないうちに脳を整理している
だから 人間は生きていける
one is unconsciously organizing their own brain.
That's why humans are able to live.
However...
ところが 彼女には それができない
...she can't do that...
From the number of leaves on street-side trees...
（神裂）
街路樹の葉っぱの数から―
...to the faces of everyone moving
in and out during rush hour periods...
ラッシュアワーであふれる
ひとりひとりの顔
雨粒の一滴一滴の形まで
...even the shape of every single drop of rain...
Her brain fills up immediately with such unnecessary information.
彼女の頭は
そんな どうでもいい記憶で―
あっという間に
埋め尽くされてしまう
Wait, just wait a second.
待てよ　待ってくれ
あんたたちは
同じ組織に所属していながら―
If you guys all belong to the same organization,
なんでインデックスに―
then why is Index calling you evil magicians?
悪い魔術師だなんて
呼ばれてんだよ？
Or, are you telling me...
それとも なにか？
...that Index is lying to me?
インデックスが
俺をダマしたって言いたいのか？
She has not lied to you.
（神裂）
彼女は ウソをついてはいませんよ
The fact that we are all members of Necessarius... nor the real reason why she's being chased...
私たちが 同じ
必要悪の教会(ネセサリウス)の人間だということも
自分が追われている本当の理由も
何も覚えていないんです
...she doesn't remember any of this...
That is why she is forced to make her own judgment...
（神裂）
だから
自分で判断するしかなかった
自分を追う魔術師は―
That it is logical to think the magicians after
the 103,000 grimoires are from the Magic Cabal.
10万3,000冊を狙う魔術結社の
人間だと思うのが 妥当だと
But Index has perfect memorization, right?
（上条）
けど インデックスには
完全記憶能力があるんだろう？
Why did she lose her memory from this past year in the first place?
そもそも あいつは なんで―
１年前からの記憶を
失っちまってるんだ？
失ったのではありません
正確には 私たちが消しました
She did not lose her memory.
We erased it, to be exact.
“消した”って どうやって…
Erased?
How?
あっ 魔術か　けど どうして…
With magic?
But why?
You were Index's friend, weren't you?
あんたは インデックスの
仲間だったんだろう？
あんたにしたって インデックスは
大切な仲間なんじゃないのか？
Wasn't Index an important friend of yours?
Then why?!
だったら どうして…
Because we had no choice but to erase her memories.
（神裂）
そうしなければ
ならなかったからです
彼女が死んでしまうからですよ
Because if we didn't... she would have died...
85% of her brain is allocated to the 103,000 grimoires.
（神裂）
彼女の脳の85パーセントは―
10万3,000冊の記憶のために
使われています
そのため 彼女は 常人の
15パーセントしか脳を使えません
That is why she can only use 15% of a normal person's brain capacity.
その15パーセントに
記憶をし続ければ 彼女の脳は…
If information keeps flooding into the remaining 15%, her brain will...
No...
そんな…
記憶を消す以外に方法は？
Other than erasing her memory, there's...
...No other way...
（神裂）ありません
（上条）いつまでだ？
When?
（神裂）
記憶の消去は
きっかり１年周期に行います
Memory erasure takes place in exact one year periods.
ちょうど そのときでなければ
記憶を消すことはできないんです
Memory erasure wouldn't be possible if it didn't occur at that exact moment.
Only three more days.
あと３日
Three days...
３日…
（神裂）
私たちに
彼女を傷つける意思はありません
We have no intention of harming her.
むしろ 私たちでなければ
彼女を救うことはできない
Rather, no one else is able to save her other than us.
Could you hand her over to us?
引き渡してくれませんか？
私が魔法名を名乗る前に
Before I mention my magic name.
And, by erasing her memory, she won't remember anything about you, no matter how much you think of her.
それに 記憶を消してしまえば―
彼女は
あなたのことも覚えていませんよ
あなたが
どれだけ彼女を思ったところで
そんな彼女を助けたところで―
Saving her brings you no benefit at all.
あなたにとって
何の益にもなりませんよ
クッ… ふざけんな！
This is wrong!
（上条）
あいつが覚えてるか
覚えていないかなんて関係あるか
Like this has anything to do with whether she remembers me or not...
分かんねえなら
ひとつだけ教えてやる
If you don't get it, then let me tell you why.
俺はインデックスの仲間なんだ
Because I'm Index's friend!
今までも これからも あいつの
味方であり続けるって決めたんだ
I've always been her friend, and I always will be!
聖書に書かれてなくたって
絶対に そうなんだよ
Even if it wasn't written in The Bible, at least this is true!
何か変だと思ったぜ
単に あいつが忘れてるだけなら
I knew something was weird.
If it's as simple as her forgetting things,
全部 説明して
誤解を解きゃいいだけの話だろう
all you need to do is explain everything and clear the misunderstanding.
なんで誤解したままにしてんだよ？
なんで敵として追い回してんだよ？
Why do you leave it as a misunderstanding?
Why do you chase after her as an enemy?
How dare you just give up on her like that?
てめえら
なに勝手に見限ってんだよ！
What about her own feeling-
あいつの気持ちを何だと…
Shut your mouth, you amateur!
うっせえんだよ ド素人が！
Don't talk as if you knew what's going on!
（神裂）
知ったような口を利くな！
What do you think we went through
all this time by taking away her memories?!
私たちが今まで―
どんな気持ちで あの子の記憶を
奪ってきたと思ってる？
あなたは
ステイルを敵視しているようですが
Apparently you see Stiyl as an enemy,
but do you even know how he felt as he watched you two?
あれが 一体 どんな気持ちで―
あの子と あなたを
見ていたと思ってるんですか？
Do you even know how much resolve he had when he presented himself as an enemy?
（神裂）
どれほどの決意のもとに
敵を名乗っているのか
Stiyl's feelings as he dishonors himself for the sake of saving his important friend...
大切な仲間のために 泥を
かぶり続けるステイルの気持ちが…
...would someone like you have any clue?!
あなたなんかに分かるんですか？
私だって頑張った！
We did what we could, too!
頑張ったんですよ！
We did, I tell you!
（神裂）
春を過ごし 夏を過ごし
We spent all spring!
All summer!
秋を過ごし 冬を過ごし
All fall!
All winter!
We created memories, and so that she didn't forget them,
思い出を作って 忘れないように
（殴る音）
たったひとつの約束をして
we made a single promise with her,
日記やアルバムを胸に抱かせて
（突き刺す音）
and we gave her a diary and album for her to carry inside her heart!
ハァ…
それでも ダメだったんですよ
And yet...
...it didn't work...
Even when we went back and made more memories with her,
イチから思い出を作り直して
何度 それを繰り返しても
no matter how many times we repeated that...
...memories of her family, friends, lovers...
家族も 親友も 恋人も
全てがゼロに返る
...they were all reset to zero...
私たちは もう耐えられません
We couldn't handle it anymore...
We couldn't bear to see her smile anymore!
これ以上 彼女の笑顔を
見続けるなんて不可能です！
（上条）
ふざけんな
That's wrong...
…んなもん
てめえらの勝手な理屈だろうが
That's just your own bullshit logic...
You didn't think for Index's sake a single moment...
インデックスのことなんざ
一瞬も考えてねえじゃねえか
Don't blame your own gutlessness on Index!
てめえの臆病のツケを―
インデックスに
押しつけてんじゃねえぞ
（上条）
１年の記憶を失うのが怖かったら
If you're so scared of seeing her lose one year's worth of memories...
次の１年に
もっと幸せな記憶を与えてやれば…
If you just give her more blessed memories the next year...
If she knows there's happiness waiting for her the year after to let her conquer the fear of losing this year's memories...
（上条）
記憶を失うのが怖くないくらいの
幸せが待ってるって分かっていれば
もう誰も
逃げ出す必要なんざねえんだから
...then no one needs to run away anymore!
Isn't that all there is to this?
たった それだけのことだろうが
てめえは力があるから
しかたなく人を守ってんのかよ？
Are you protecting people just because you have power?
違うだろう　そうじゃねえだろう！
No, right?
That's not how it is, right?!
守りたいものがあるから
力を手に入れたんだろうが！
You acquired power because  you have something you want to protect, right?
てめえは何のために力をつけた？
Why did you acquire power?
Who did you want to protect with those hands?
てめえは
その手で誰を守りたかった？
Then what the hell are you doing here?!
だったら てめえは
こんな所で何やってんだ？
With that much power,
それだけの力があって―
with such a versatile power,
これだけ万能の力を持ってるのに
なんで…
why are you... so... incompetent...
なんで そんなに無能なん…
…だ
（神裂）
ハァ…
All done?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
もういいかな？
（黒子(くろこ)）
待ってください お姉様
そんなに急がなくても…
Wait for me, Oneesama.
You don't need to be in such a hurry.
（美琴(みこと)）
黒子 あんたね
Kuroko, you...
“門限 門限”って言ってたわりに
あちこち連れ回して
While you keep saying curfew, curfew,
you've been dragging me to place after place...
（美琴）遅れても知らないわよ
（黒子）お姉様！
I won't be held responsible if we're back late.
Oneesama~
（黒子）
どうしたんですの？
What happened?
うん？　これは…
This is...
A razor sharp cut like that...
（黒子）
あの鋭利な切り口
気体制御系の能力者の
いたずらでしょうか？
Perhaps, a prank by someone with robotic control powers?
（美琴）
いたずらねえ
A prank, huh?
A task for Judgment, obviously.
風紀委員(ジャッジメント)のお仕事ですわね
ちょっと 黒子！
この荷物 どうすんのよ？
Hold it, Kuroko!
What am I going to do with all this stuff?
もう…
どうしましたの？　お姉様
What's the matter, Oneesama?
（美琴）何でも
（黒子）うん？
Nothing.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻(とうま)？
Touma...
ンッ… ここは…
Where am I?
ウッ！　いって…
Damn it hurts...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻！　ダメだよ まだ起きちゃ
Touma, you shouldn't get up yet!
日が昇ってる
…てことは ひと晩明けたのか
The sun's in the sky...
...which means a night has gone by...
What time is it now?
今 何時だ？
Not one night.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ひと晩じゃないよ
（上条）えっ？
３日
Three days.
Three days?!
３日？
なんで
そんなに眠ってたんだ？　俺
How could I have slept for that long?
Three days...
３日…
Memory erasure takes place in exact one year periods.
記憶の消去は
きっかり１年周期に行います
（神裂）
あと３日
Only three more days.
Touma, what's wrong?
当麻 どうしたの？
どこか痛い？
Does it hurt somewhere?
いや…
No.
（上条）
インデックスが
俺のことを覚えてるってことは―
The fact that Index still remembers me means the memory erasure hasn't taken place yet.
まだ記憶の消去は行われていない
And neither does Index seem any different.
それに インデックスの様子も
変わってないみたいだしな
良かった
Everything's okay...
No, it isn't!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）よくないよ
（上条）えっ？
I didn't know of anything.
私 何にも知らなかった
Komoe said that you were lying unconscious in the middle of the road.
当麻が道路の真ん中に倒れてたって
小萌(こもえ)が言ってた
Komoe was also the one that carried
your beaten body back to the apartment.
ボロボロになった当麻を担いで―
アパートに連れてきたのも
小萌だった
私は 何にも気づかないで…
I didn't realize anything.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻が
ほかの魔術師と戦ってることなんて
I didn't think at all that you were fighting against other magicians.
これっぽっちも考えないで
私は…
I...
私は 当麻を助けられなかった
I... couldn't save you...
何だよ？
このグルグル巻きの包帯
What's with this ridiculous bandage wrapping?
A bit much, don't you think?
ちょっと
大げさすぎるんじゃねえの？
I thought that was necessary to heal wounds.
一応
治すためには そうしとかないとね
It's not as reliable as magic, but...
魔術みたいにはいかないけど
You're right.
そうだな
魔術なんか使わなくても
大丈夫だろう
It'll be fine even if you don't use magic.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ンッ… 当麻
（上条）うん？
Touma.
当麻！　この期に及んで
まだ魔術を信じてないんだね？
Touma, you still don't believe in magic even after all this, do you?!
片思いちゃんみたいに
かたくななんだよ？
You're as stubborn as a person with a one-sided love!
That's not what I meant.
（上条）そういう意味じゃねえよ
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）えっ？
できることなら―
If at all possible, I don't want to see the look on your face when you speak about magic.
お前が魔術 語ってるときの顔って
あんま見たくねえからな
I see...
そっか　私 また目覚めてたんだ？
I woke up again?
うん？ “目覚めた”？
Woke up?
うん　けど そのときのことは
あんまり突っ込んでほしくないかも
But, I don't think I want to hear about how I am when I wake up.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
意識がないときの声って
寝言みたいで恥ずかしいからね
The voice I have when I'm unconscious is like talking in dreams... it's very embarrassing...
Besides...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）それに…
（上条）うん？
なんだか どんどん
冷たい機械になっていくみたいで
...it feels like I'm gradually becoming a cold machine...
...and it scares me...
怖いんだよ
（上条）
ごめん
Sorry...
It's okay, idiot.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）いいんだよ バカ
（上条）うん？
Want to eat something?
何か食べる？
Umm... Index... -san?
あの… インデックスさん？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
うん？　私はシスターさんなので
看病くらいできるんだよ
I am a Sister,
so I know how to take care of a sick person, at least.
W-Well... please allow me the time to think over this deeply, God...
い… いや　とりあえず
深く考える時間をください 神さま
Why?
なんで？　食欲ない？
Not hungry?
Ah-
は～い！
Coming!
Komoe, perhaps?
小萌かな？
What are you doing in front of my home?
（小萌）
あれ？
家(うち)の前で 何やってるんです？
Kamijyo-chan!
（小萌）
上条ちゃん！　何だか知らないけど
お客さんみたいです
I'm not sure what's going on, but we have some guests.
（上条）てめえら　今更 何しに…
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）ふ～ん…
You guys!
What are you guys doing here now-
Hmm...
You can't even run away easily with that body of yours.
その体じゃ 簡単に
逃げ出すこともできないみたいだね
そうか　インデックスは今まで
あいつらから１人で逃げてきたんだ
I see...
Index has been running away from these people on her own...
けど 俺というケガ人を
背負うことになれば 話は違う
...but if she has to carry the burden of an injured person in me, then it's a different story...
インデックスを より安全で
確実に保護するために 俺を…
In order to more efficiently and safely secure Index,
they want to use me as...
Go away!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
帰って！
I beg you, I'll go anywhere with you.
お願いだから
私なら どこへでも行くから
I'll do anything for you!
私なら 何でもするから！
Index!
（上条）
インデックス！
Please, I beg you, please.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
本当に… 本当にお願いだから
お願いだから
もう当麻を傷つけないで！
Please, don't hurt Touma anymore!
～♪
Next Episode
Tonight, at midnight,
（上条）
今夜12時　インデックスの
記憶を消去する儀式が始まる
the ritual to erase Index's memories will take place.
But I won't give up.
だが 俺は諦めない
絶対に お前を助け出す！
I will get you out of there!
次回 「十二時(リミット)」
Next time, "Limit".
When science and magic cross paths,
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる
this epic will begin!